# Jume Brice

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER | TEAM LEAD

https://github.com/Jumeb | bricejume@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jume-njah/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

High performing team leader with a passion for the implementation of highly responsive web platforms, with the use of very little third party packages to improve user experience and reduce load times. Confident in the ability to lead a team of talents in the art of atomic design principles to effectively complete task in the shortest time possible yet bringing highly accurate and pixel perfect implementation.

# AREA OF EXPERTISE

✓ NextJS	✓ ReactJS	✔ React Native	✓ TypeScript
✓ CSS	✓ Tailwind CSS	✓ HTML5	✓ Redux JS
✔ Project Managemen	t 🗸 Team management	✓ NodeJS	✔ Problem solving

#### CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

**Code base optimization:** Reduced up to 60% of third party dependencies for GasVisor mobile application and delivering an improvement of 30% user experience.

**Fast implementation:** Track record of consistently delivering 98% pixel perfect implementation of UI designs from the UI/UX department with no third party packages and with an increase of 30% deployment of new features.

**Team work:** Over 2+ years of working in teams and more than 7+ months leading a frontend development team to greatly cut down on delivering highly responsive implementations thus a 20% increase in the release of new features.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Chief of Engineering, Camsol Technologies UG, AUG 2023 - Present

In this engineering leadership role, reponsibilities entails managing a portfolio of 2 projects one mobile and the other web value over 20million euros.

- Over seeing the implementation of the Calendar scheduler for the web platform to manage clients schedule which increased user growth by 10% and reducing package dependency by 5%.
- Leading the mobile team in the development of the state management using redux leading to 50% reduction of code and 40% increase in efficiency.
- Working in collaboration with the UI/UX department to realise implentation of designs leading 20% faster realise of new web features.

• Leading team members through design implementation and other tips and tricks on how to correctly inspect figma designs and pay attention to intricate details for the development process which is leading to an increase in team collaboration.

# Lead Frontend developer, Camsol Technologies UG, DEC 2022 - AUG 2023

Held accountability for the growth of teams for the first time and also working on a small project which later grew to be worth millions.

- Worked in collaboration with the Product owner for GasVisor mobile application in rebuilding the architecture of the code base to follow atomic design principles increase navigation of the code base by 70%.
- Removing of high import cost packages with little importance and building replacement components to reduce app bundle size.
- Introduced GitHub actions for automatic generation of Android APKs and oversaw the building of iOS testflights which led to an increase of platform specific styles in the code base.
- Developed branching strategies, automated build/integration checks, and simplified deployment patterns, on GitHub which boosted team velocity by 28%.
- Worked under a mentor in other webplatforms about leadership and problem solving leading to a 70% increase in my leadership skills.

# Frontend Developer, Camsol Technologies UG, | MARCH 2022 - DEC 2022

Entry level position at the company and learning the work structure and finding great mentors to guide on my tech career.

- Started with the development of a mobile application for Romis for the management of their online purchase and financial records using React Native, Contentful with GraphQL for data manipulation following modern design patterns and code architecture.
- Collaboration with the PO and working on the application single handedly, I continuously deployed my progress to GitHub with a design workflow to automate the build process of the application.
- Troubleshooting known and unknown issues from my code base, developing and integration 5 screen every week.
- Participated in client negotiations and talks about way forward.
- Read several documentations provided by the PO owner on various principles like token generation, model creation on contentful, playground for GraphQL and ways in writing queries.
- Maintained this application and delivered on client request until the contract was over which led to me being recognized and given better opportunities.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor in Engineering,** University of Buea, Faculty of Engineering and technolgy | SEPT 2017 - AUG 2021

- Relavant course work: Introduction to Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Algorithms, and Data Structuress, Software Development Life Cycle, and Cloud Service Oriented Architectures.
- 6 months Professional internship: Carried out internship at Digital Renter, Buea Cameroon, mentored by the CEO Mr Fongoh Martin, in the development of mobile applications using React native and API integration from a PHP backend. Also learned the importance of Pixel perfect implementation.

#### TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- **Proficient:** React, NextJS, CSS, SASS, TailwindCSS, React Native, JavaScript, TypeScript, Problem-Solving.
- Familiar with: NodeJS & Express, MongoDB, Directus, Heroku, Vercel, Docker
- Tools: VScode, Jira, Bitbucket, GitHub, Postman, MongoDB Compass, GitHub actions. Xcode.

#### **PROJECTS**

### Flavours Since AUG 2023

It is a B2B, B2C platform to aid in the connection of young food chefs either in pastries or meals to connect to potential food consumers.

- Work on the frontend implementation of the vision and tools that would be used to simplify management and financial records of young food chefs.
- Work on the tools to easy management of staff related to young food chefs and delivery to clients
- Work on the back APIs for CRUB functionalities requested in the frontend using NodeJS and MongoDB.
- Work on creating and updating Data models for each data table in the backend.

## Portfolio Since JAN 2024

It is a personal portfolio website built with CSS, Tailwind and NextJS to show my skills and other projects I worked on.